<resources>
    <string name="app_name">201735016</string>

    <string name="back_button">Do you really want to close the application?</string>
    <string name="yes">Yes</string>
    <string name="no">No</string>


    <string name="worldwar1_1">World War I is one of the bloodiest wars in the world in which dozens of states participated. The Ottoman State is one of the most important states in this war, especially due to its strategic location. World War I, in which legendary conflicts took place, is a war fought in the last period of the Ottoman Empire\n\nThe Causes of the First World War and the Ottoman Empire in the First World War.\n\nThe First World War started for many reasons and took its place in history as one of the bloodiest and biggest wars in the world. The causes of World War I are discussed in different groups as special causes and general reasons.\n\n<b>GENERAL CAUSES</b>\n- Colonialism\n- Nationalism\n- The arms race\n- Interstate blocking</string>
    <string name="worldwar1_2">SPECIAL CAUSES\n\nThe desire of Germany and the British colonies\n- Russia\'s idea of landing in warm seas that has been going on for hundreds of years\n- Alsace-Loren region with rich coal deposits between Germany and France\n - The existence of Orthodox-Slavic conflicts between Russia and Austria-Hungary is among the special reasons of the war.\n\nThe beginning of World War I brought the tension between private and general reasons to the highest level. However, the situation that caused the war to begin was the killing of the Austro-Hungarian crown by a young Serbian while wandering to the battlefield. Thereupon, the Austro-Hungarian Empire declared war on Serbia and Russia declared that it assumed the protection of Serbia. Thus, the war officially started between Russia and Austria-Hungary. After the war started, the states that had previously blocked out started to fight against each other.</string>
    <string name="worldwar1_3"><b>THE REASONS OF THE OTTOMAN EMPİRE TO ENTER THE WAR</b>\n\nAt the beginning of World War I, the Ottoman Empire initially acted with the idea of staying neutral, but saw that it could not escape from the war in the future. Thereupon, the obligation to go to war arose.\nThe reason for the Ottoman Empire to go to war is;\n - Getting back the lost places,\n- German admiration of the government\nThe idea that Germany will win the war,\n- He entered the war on the side of Germany for reasons such as getting rid of political isolation.</string>
    <string name="worldwar1_4"><b>FRONTS FOUGHT BY THE OTTOMAN EMPİRE</b>\n\nThe Ottoman Empire fought on three different fronts in the First World War. These are referred to as attack, defense and aid fronts.\nOffensive fronts; Caucasian, canal fronts\nDefense front; Çanakkale, Syria - Palestine, Iraq, Hejaz - Yemen\nHelp fronts are; It appears as Macedonia, Romania and Galicia.</string>
    <string name="worldwar1_5"><b>GENERAL CONSEQUENCES OF WORLD WAR 1</b>\n\nWorld War 2 is a war that lasts for 4 years. The First World War, which started in 1914, ended in 1918 with the Armistice of Mondros. As a result of the war;\n- The Entente States won the war.\n- National states were established instead of empires.\n- There has been a change in the map of Europe\n- Millions of people died in World War I, one of the bloodiest wars in the world\n- States have established new regimes\n- It is known that it prepared the ground for the Second World War in terms of the results of the World War</string>
    <string name="worldwar2_1">World War II, the bloodiest war in human history, is a war that took place between 1939 and 1945 and was one of the worst catastrophes for human history. Here is all the information you are looking for about the history of the second world war, its causes, summary and consequences\nGreat destructions occurred during the Second World War, in which over 65 million people lost their lives. 33% of those who died were soldiers, 65% were civilians.\n\nWorld War 2 - Summary\nThe Second World War is a great war that has caused great disasters in human history. The war, which took place between 1939 and 1945 and resulted in the death of over 65 million people, went down in history as a black mark</string>
    <string name="worldwar2_2">Epidemic diseases broke out with the Second World War and economic crises emerged. It also caused the country borders to be re-determined. In this respect, it has been one of the greatest disasters and wars in human history. Although 75 years have passed, it is still a war whose effects continue and the heavy balance of the war is extremely frightening\nDuring the Second World War, Italy, Germany and Japan agreed between them and formed the "Triple Axis" group\nThe Nazi administration, which came to power in Germany, defended the superiority of the German race. As a result of this, he declared that he did not recognize the Versailles Peace Treaty and started to occupy. Czechoslovakia and Austria were under German occupation.</string>
    <string name="worldwar2_3">Against the Axis Group, France and Britain formed the "Allied States" group. Later, Russia and the USA joined the Allied Powers group. Germany signed a neutrality agreement with Russia and declared war against Poland in 1939\nFrance and England have given collateral to Poland. As a result, Poland also declared war on Germany. As a result of all these developments, the Second World War, one of the worst disasters in human history, started\nWith the start of the Second World War, Germany shared its occupied Polish lands with the Russians. In the future, the Germans; Norway, Denmark, France and the Netherlands occupied their lands</string>
    <string name="worldwar2_4">In this process, Italy occupied Albanian lands. Later, he attacked Greece, but did not succeed in this attempt. Upon these developments, Germany turned towards the Balkans and captured the lands of Hungary, Greece and Romania\nAfter the Germans posed a threat to the Balkans, Russia joined the allied states group. Due to the Japanese attack on the Pearl Harbor base of the USA, the United States participated in the war by taking part in the Allied Group</string>
    <string name="worldwar2_5">CAUSES AND RESULTS OF THE SECOND WORLD WAR\n\nAs in every war, the Second World War has important reasons for the states participating in the war. We can list the reasons that led to this war as follows:\n- States that suffered defeats in the First World War are obliged to sign agreements with severe conditions\n- Japan\'s desire to prevent the European invasion from happening in the Asian continent\n- As a result of the First World War, the resultant fights redefine the borders of the country\n- The consequences of the First World War are against the Italian and German states as relations of interest\nAll these developments are the events that caused the Second World War to break out</string>
    <string name="worldwar2_6">The Second World War, which caused great destruction, is a war with important consequences for human history. These results are as follows;\n- Germany is divided into West and East Germany\n- United Nations has been established\n- The states that defended democracy were the winners of the Second World War\n\nColonial activities decreased significantly after the Second World War\n- Turkey has approached the United States\n- Russia has gained an important power in the Balkans\n- NATO and Warsaw Pact have been established</string>


</resources>